你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
等等  等等  不要
Wait. Wait, no!
有点晕  除此之外  我想我没事
A little dizzy, but otherwise, I think I'm okay.
欢迎加入  卡米拉
Welcome to the team, Kamilla.
你的创造是意料之外的
Your creation was unplanned,
但我知道有你加入必能为我所用
but I know you'll make a useful addition.
另一个我在哪
Where's my counterpart?
无需再担心她了
She's no longer a problem now.
在爱瑞丝意识到我不在之前我没有太多时间
I don't have much time before Iris realizes I'm gone,
所以听我说  这很重要
so listen to me, this is important.
六年前
Six years ago,
我创造了一台能够将光转化成能源的设备
I created a device capable of converting light into energy.
我把它称作棱镜折射器
I called it the Prismatic Refractor.
它看起来是这个样子的
It looked like this.
我需要你们帮我取回来
I need you to retrieve it for me.
-它真美  -那是一个复制品
- It's beautiful. - That's a replica.
我在镜像宇宙里做的
I made it here in the Mirrorverse,
但我的R-CEM不能使用它
but my R-CEM rejected it,
我想需要原版的那个才能正常工作
I believe it needs the original in order to function.
R-CEM是什么
What's the R-CEM?
那是确保我的长期计划能成功的东西
A thing that will ensure the success of my long term plans.
我们从哪开始
Where do we start?
我的丈夫  约瑟夫  他
My husband, Joseph, he...
低估了折射器的价值
underestimated the value of the Refractor
几个月前将它卖给了水星实验室
and sold it to Mercury Labs a few months ago.
想办法混进去  用复制品把原版换出来
Find a way in, replace the replica out with the original,
然后拿给我
and you bring it to me.
-别让我失望  -保证成功
- Do not let me down. - Success is assured.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第十五集
我已经黑进了这个星球上
I've officially hacked every Quantum Kinematic database
每一个量子运动学数据库
on the planet.
你们知道关于人造神速力我有何发现吗
You know what I found out about Artificial Speed Forces?
斯旺造过一个  仅此一个
Thawne built one, and that's it.
我想他不会告诉我们
And I doubt he's gonna tell us
鉴于他如今附身了我们的朋友纳什
seeing how he's Linda Blaired our pal Nash,
琳达·布莱尔在电影《驱魔人》中饰演被魔鬼附身的小女孩
他现在想把我们全干掉
and you know, he kinda wants to murder the hell out of us.
如果斯旺能想出来怎么做  我们也能
If Thawne can figure it out, then so can we.
与此同时
In the meantime,
我们得确保闪电侠不会失去他的能力
we need to make sure the Flash doesn't lose his powers.
神速力可能没了
The Speed Force may be gone,
但是在你的DNA里仍有残余的速度
but there's still a residual amount of speed left in your DNA.
在我们弄清楚残余多少之前
Until we figure out how much,
我们得控制你的速度输出
we need to manage your speed output.
-怎么做  -我把它叫做神速力计量表
- How do we do that? - I call it the Speed Gauge.
它会测量你的神速力强度
It will measure the intensity of the velocity you're using
并用颜色表示出来  现在  黑色
by color. So, right now, it's black.
那是中性状态  表示你此刻处于静止
That's neutral--means you're not using any speed at all.
如果你使用了最小量的神速力  它会变绿
If you're using a minimal amount, that's green.
下一个速度范围是黄色  接着是桔色
The yellow is next, then orange,
很明显  红色就是最大量了
and obviously red is the maximum amount.
现阶段
At this point,
不建议你超过绿色的范围
I don't recommend operating beyond green.
我们指的不止是奔跑
And we're not just talking about running, okay?
-还有高速思考  -高速愈合
- Speed thinking-- - Speed healing--
闪电时间
Flash time.
所有这些活动都会消耗你的超能力
All of these things could deplete your meta-abilities.
-你必须小心行事  -各位  这没那么简单
- You have to be careful. - Guys, it's not that simple.
我还要维持这座城市的安全
I'm supposed to keep the city safe.
闪电侠小队  我是你们的朋友纳什
Team Flash! It's your pal, Nash.
放我出去
Let me out!
大伙  我们确定那是纳什吗
Guys, are we sure that's Nash?
也可能是斯旺在躲猫猫
Or Thawne playing possum?
我们去搞清楚
Let's find out.
我听说对于卡弗的反腐调查
I hear you've got an update for me
你有新进展要告诉我
on the Carver RICO investigation.
仅仅筛了一遍文件之后
Just sifting through the paperwork,
我找到了多处掩盖罪行的证据
I found evidence of multiple cover-ups.
凶杀案被记录为意外
Homicides being filed as accidents,
失踪人口的案子被伪造的文书抹掉
missing person cases buried by falsified paperwork.
而所有的受害者都有一个共同点
And every victim has one thing in common.
你认为卡弗在中城警局有个内鬼吗
You think Carver has a mole inside CCPD?
有人一直在帮他逃避犯罪指控
Somebody has been helping him evade criminal charges.
问题是  为什么
The question is, why?
这些发现非常了不起  乔
This is, uh, outstanding work, Joe,
但是调查一个内鬼
but investigating a mole,
那是内务部的工作  不是我们的
that's--that's a job for internal affairs, not for us.
我们不能相信内务部
We can't trust I.A.
在找出卡弗收买谁之前  任何人都不能相信
or anybody until we find out who Carver's bought.
巴里也同意
I mean, Barry agrees.
等等  闪电侠也看过这些文件了吗
Hold on, Flash has seen these files?
是的
Yeah.
乔  这事和超能力者无关
Joe, this is not meta-related business.
你是不是借此在处理个人恩怨呢
Is there a chance that this is becoming personal?
鉴于卡弗对爱瑞丝的所为
I mean, I would totally understand
我完全能理解
given what Carver's done to Iris.
这事在于将一个罪犯绳之以法
This is still about bringing a criminal to justice.
我们会的
And we will,
但是  乔  这是你升做队长的第一年
but Joe, this is your first year as captain.
如果你的人认为你怀疑他们中有内鬼
If your people think you suspect one of them of being a mole,
而你又判断错了
and you're wrong...
等着瞧吧
Have a look.
所以这个斯旺
So this Thawne--
取得红眼和频率
got the red eyes and vibrates,
但他也是威尔斯吗
but he's also a Wells?
没错  是他
Yeah. That's him.
你怎么...
How did you--
最近我一直经常看到威尔斯
I've been seeing a lot of Wells lately.
我是说
I mean,
在我脑海里  经常看到
up here. A lot.
我不知道有多少个威尔斯
I don't know how many there are,
但魔术师威尔斯  很讨厌
but the wizard Wells, annoying.
法国威尔斯
French Wells--
纽约市威尔斯
New York City Wells--
其实他还行  然后是哈里·威尔斯
actually he's all right. And then Harry Wells.
纳什  哈里死了  他们都死了
Nash, Harry's dead. They're all dead.
你们应该来看看这个
Hey, guys? I think you should see this.
走吧
Let's go.
拜托  放我出去
Let-- come on. Let me out!
初看  纳什的脑电波几乎是完全正常的
So, at first glance, Nash's brainwaves seem totally normal.
没有异常或不一致
No anomalies or inconsistencies.
但是我用三维查看的时候
But when I take a look at them in 3D,
似乎有许多脑电波
it appears that there are multiple brainwaves
错综复杂地交织在一起
intricately tangled together.
多元宇宙在危机中消失的时候
When the Multiverse collapsed in Crisis
所有的威尔斯肯定是全都转移到
all of the Wellses must have channeled into
唯一一个幸存的二重身上了
the only surviving doppelganger.
多重心理在纳什的脑中住了下来
Multiple psyches camped out in Nash's brain.
就像上千个泰勒·德登一样
It's like Tyler Durden times a thousand.
电影《搏击俱乐部》人主角
泰勒·德登  这例子举得好
Tyler Durden. Great reference.
搏击俱乐部的规则是
"First rule of fight club is--"
我们能不聊《搏击俱乐部》吗
Kay, can we not talk about "Fight Club"?
我说完了
Yeah, that's it.
到底有多少个威尔斯
So how many Wells are we talking about here?
多元宇宙中有多少个宇宙
How many universes were there in the multiverse?
什么
What?
等等  不  这也不对啊
Okay, wait, no, this doesn't make any sense.
斯旺根本都不算是威尔斯
I mean, Thawne wasn't even a real Wells.
他杀了哈里森·威尔斯  抢占了他的身体
He killed Harrison Wells, took over his body,
骗了我们几个月
and fooled us for months.
我们在说的就是这个疯子
This is the psychopath we're talking about
他想要霸占我的身体
that is trying to take over my body!
我们要在他再次出现之前抓到他
Let's get him out before he resurfaces!
快点
Come on!
没有任何医疗手续或是设备
I mean, there's no medical procedure or device
可以分离脑电波
that could separate brainwaves.
在这个傻地球上是不行  但是
Not on this stupid Earth there's not, but hello,
我可是多元宇宙穿越者  对吧
Multiversal traveler, anyone? Right?
我包里有神经元连接器
I have a neuro-splicer here in my bag.
你能去拿一下吗
Can you-- can you get it please?
会成功的
Will work just fine.
其实它还帮我在地球26上
Actually help me out stop an invasion
阻止了一场通灵海星大入侵
of psychic starfish on Earth 26.
在小的...  就是这个
In the little-- yeah, that's it.
场面一点不太好看
That was not pretty,
虽然说实话  我不知道连接器
although, to be honest, I don't know
是否能一次分离上千个脑电波
if the splicer can separate thousands of brainwaves all at once.
如果我们用你护手上的
It will be if we supercharge it
电磁脉冲给它充电就可以
with the EMP from your gauntlet.
没错
Yes.
是的  护手  没错
Yes, the gauntlet, yes!
要确保在你给电磁脉冲充电时
Just make sure that when you charge the EMP
用每米1500伏特
that it's 1,500 volts per meter,
-不然你会危害到...  -我知道
- otherwise, you'll risk-- - I know, I know.
-不然我就会...  -把电路烧坏
- Otherwise, I'll-- - Fry the circuitry.
-我知道  -西斯科  等等
- I got it. - Cisco, wait.
他自始至终都是斯旺吗
That was Thawne the whole time?
他跑不远的
He could't gotten far.
他没有超能力  不能穿越时间
He doesn't have his powers, he can't time travel.
他可以
Yes, he can.
看看我们  闪电侠
Look at us, Flash.
同病相怜的人
Two peas in a pod.
两个对速度限制感到沮丧挫败的极速者
Just two speedsters frustrated by the limits of their speed.
我和你完全不一样
I'm nothing like you.
不  要拿到神速力的人是我
No, I'm the one who's gonna get his speed back.
等我恢复后
When I do,
当我控制这个身体时
when I gain control of this body,
当我和神速力重新连接时
when I reconnect to my Speed Force,
你
you--
你就会软弱到阻止不了我  对吧
you're gonna be too weak to stop me, aren't you?
就像你无力拯救你女儿一样
Just like you were powerless to save your daughter.
我想念我的小极速者
I miss my Little Runner.
诺拉从来都不是你的
Nora was never yours.
杀了我吧
Do it. Do it.
我想知道我死后  你还会剩下多少神速力
I wonder, how much speed will you have left after I'm gone?
巴里  不要
Barry, no!
他又耍了我们一次
He tricked us. Again.
应该想到给EMP增压
Should've known supercharging the EMP
会导致反冲循环
would cause a recoil loop.
斯旺总是有后备计划
Thawne always has a backup plan.
我检查了录像
I checked the footage.
斯旺只去了实验室档案馆
Thawne only went to the Starchives,
没去其他地方  纳什怎么样了
nowhere else. How's Nash?
好点了  至少现在你不想杀他了
Better, now that you're not trying to kill him.
你真的会下手吗
Were you really gonna do it?
我不知道
I don't know.
纳什需要帮助  不是重伤
Nash needs help, not maiming.
你不能呆在这里  巴里
You can't be here, Barry.
为什么  因为你的神速力计量表
Why not? Because your Speed Gauge
记录了大量的神速力损失
registered a massive loss of speed,
也就是不仅使用能力会造成影响
which means not only does using your powers affect it,
你的愤怒也会
but so does your anger.
凯瑟琳  我会没事的  好吗
Caitlin, I'll be fine, all right?
如果需要速度  我会用终极速度-X这种增强剂
And if I need more speed, I'll use a booster like Velocity-X--
太好了
Oh, great,
所以你现在要开始打神速力激素了
so you're just gonna start taking speed steroids now?
巴里  我们所做过的所有测试
Barry, every test we've run
都显示你的生理结构发生了大转变
says that physiology, you have changed drastically,
所以我们不知道终极速度-X会对你怎样
so we have no idea what Velocity-X would do to you.
它可能会伤到你  也可能伤到别人
It could hurt you, it could hurt others--
别人已经受到伤害了
Other people are already hurt.
我是说  我们完全不知道斯旺
I mean, we have no idea what Thawne is doing
现在对纳什做了什么
to Nash right now.
他还可能对你造成更大的伤害
And he could do even more damage to you
如果你让他再次影响到你
if he just gets under your skin again.
我知道这对你来说很难
Look, I know this is hard for you,
但你必须离开
but you need to leave.
在他身边  你无法信任自己
You can't trust yourself around him.
你的意思是你无法信任我在他身边
What you mean is you can't trust me around him.
好了  收到了你关于斯旺的信息
Okay, got your message about Thawne,
所以我带来了  圣水
so I brought, uh, holy water,
大蒜
uh, garlic,
木桩
wooden stake,
盐  显而易见
salt, obviously,
还有通灵板
and Ouija board.
-塞西尔  -怎么了
- Cecile. - What?
这是个驱魔仪式
It's an exorcism.
没有过分准备一说
It's not like we can be too prepared.
这不是什么吸血鬼魔鬼
This isn't some kind of vampire demon,
这是
this is...
这是其他的东西
this is something else.
我的天
Oh, my God.
纳什内心所感受的一切
Everything that Nash is feeling inside,
依然只是纯粹的仇恨
it's still just raw hatred.
我们认为是斯旺的
What we think of as Thawne
其实只是一连串负超光速粒子
is actually just a series of negative tachyons
集中在纳什身体中
inside Nash's body.
所以我们要用正超光速粒子冲击他
So we gotta hit him with positive tachyons
逼出斯旺
to force Thawne out.
所以我们需要PTD  正超光速粒子装置
That's why we need the PTD, or the Positive Tachyon Device,
而不是通灵版  无意冒犯
and not a Ouija board. No offense.
好吧  那你需要我来做什么
Okay, so, what do you need me for?
你要做我的斯旺探测器
You're gonna be my Thawne detector.
我需要你用通灵监视纳什
I need you to psychically monitor Nash
告诉我他什么时候从斯旺的影响中解脱
and tell me when he's free from Thawne's influence.
你觉得你能做到吗
You think you can handle that?
在目睹了斯旺对我们所爱之人做的事之后
After what Thawne did to the people that we love?
当然可以
Hell yeah.
那是时候驱魔了
Then it's time for an exorcism.
地球719
八年前
崇拜植物  一群蠢货
Worshipping a plant. People are idiots.
孩子
Hey, hey. Kid!
你怎么进来  你是怎么避过我的...
How'd you get in here? How'd you get past my...
安保无人机
Security drone.
好吧  你是谁  你叫什么名字
All right, who are you? What's your name?
玛雅  你真拿到了
It's Maya. You actually caught it.
以前从没有人把血花
No one's ever pulled the Blood Bloom
从沃普嘴中拿出来过来
out of the Wollip's mouth before.
是  对  那个沃普  孩子
Yeah, right. Well, the Wollip, kid,
只是个被本地人做了手脚的雕像而已
is just a statue rigged by the locals, that's all.
-我知道  -你知道
- I know. - You do?
你要把宝藏从花里拿出来吗
You gonna get the treasure out of the Bloom?
是啊  我要把宝藏从花里拿出来
Yeah, I'm gonna get the treasure out of the Bloom.
-你是指水晶吗  -我是指宝藏
- What--you mean the crystals? - No, I mean the treasure.
-什么宝藏  -里边的
- What treasure? - Inside.
我不知道它们...
I don't know if they-hey, hey, hey--oh!
这个价钱比那些破水晶贵三倍
This is worth three times more than those dumb crystals.
很厉害  孩子
I'm impressed, kid.
但你坏了一个规则
But you broke one of the rules.
你看  从不要给任何人任何东西
You see, you never give anybody anything
除非你能获得什么
unless you get something in return.
帽子不错
Nice hat.
快走吧
Now scram.
当你告诉你父母帽子是哪里来的时候
And when you tell your parents where you got the hat from,
让他们知道你凭实力得到的
make sure you tell them you earned it.
我没有父母
I don't have parents.
现在没有了
Not anymore.
玛雅
Maya.
你想要干我这一行吗
How'd you like to do what I do?
-那是什么  -终结流言
- What's that? - Myth busting.
终结考古学的流言
Archeological myth busting.
就是干这些的  你听起来喜欢吗
That's what all this is for. You like the sound of that?
-喜欢  -好
- Yes. - Yeah.
我觉得你一定会很出色
Yeah, I think you'd be good at it.
第一个规则就是  战利品就是一切
And rule number one: the prize is everything.
你觉得你能记住吗
Think you can remember that?
战利品就是一切  小菜一碟
The prize is everything. Easy peasy.
西斯科  纳什在疼痛中  发生什么了
Cisco, Nash is hurting. What's happening?
我不确定  这是我第一次驱魔
I'm not sure. It's my first exorcism.
欢迎来到地狱
Welcome to Hell.
我不可能在这
I can't be here.
太晚了
Too late.
纳什现在正在经历的痛苦
All the pain that's being brought up in Nash--
快让他撑不住了
it's overwhelming him.
这就是斯旺获得力量的方法
It's how Thawne gains his strength.
-他以别人的痛苦为食  -那他正在吸食纳什
- He feeds on that pain. - Then he's feasting on Nash.
水星实验室
我们在《公民报》听说
From what we've heard at the "Citizen,"
水星实验室在清洁能源上有重大的突破
Mercury Labs is making massive developments in clean energy.
没错
We are,
麦吉博士非常高兴能跟你们分享这些
and Dr. McGee is thrilled to speak to you about it.
你们在这里稍等一下  我去叫她出来
If you'll wait right here, I'll go grab her.
-谢谢你  -不要紧
- Thank you. - Mm-hmm.
就是这里吗
Is this the place?
根据我的读数  棱镜折射器应该
According to my readings, the Prismatic Refractor is...
在这
Here.
干得漂亮
Nice
-又一个光属性的超能力者  -肯定是跟卡夫一伙的
- Another light-based meta? - Must be one of Carver's.
那就意味着他也想要折射器
Which means he's after the Refractor too.
我们得离开这里
We gotta get out of here.
但是折射器  伊娃说过
But the Refractor. Eva said--
不用担心
No, don't worry.
我们让闪电侠搞定她
We'll let the Flash handle this one.
遇险广播
超能力者抢劫
一个超能力者正在抢劫水星实验室
It's a meta robbery at Mercury Labs.
好的  我在那里与你会合
Okay, I'll meet you there.
不用  我和冰霜能搞定
No, Frost and I can handle this.
你需要留在这里保存你的神速力
You need to stay here and conserve your speed.
医生的吩咐
Doctor's orders.
-但是  凯特琳  我  -医生的吩咐
- But, Caitlin, I-- - Doctor's orders.
-把那个东西放下  -不存在的
- Put that down. - Not happening.
那好  敬酒不吃吃罚酒
Fine. Have it your way.
你就是那个冰霜女皇啊
So you're the ice queen, huh?
别人都叫你什么
What do they call you?
叫我  烈日
Call me... Sunshine.
冰霜对烈日  猜猜谁融化
Ice versus sun. Guess who melts?
闪电侠  我说过我能搞定
Flash? I said I had this handled.
不用担心  用不了多久
Don't worry. This won't take long.
闪电侠  别
Flash, no.
光博士向你们问好
Dr. Light sends her regards.
冰霜
Frost!
在黑洞都传你是个狠角色
Word around Black Hole is you're quite the badass.
你可以是我们的一员
You could've been one of us.
不许动
Freeze!
冰霜
Frost.
你还好吗
You okay?
所以现在我们面对的不只是一两个
So we're looking at not one or two,
而是三个来自黑洞的光系刺客
but three Black Hole light assassins.
而且他们所有人都是受雇于卡夫
All of them are under Carver's payroll.
每一个都比上一个强
Each one more powerful than the last.
烈日把冰霜的光博士的光子子弹伤口撕开了
Sunshine reopened Frost's wound from Dr. Light's photon bullet.
她的冰疗愈在慢慢治疗她
Her ice healing's working overtime.
这都是我的错
This is my fault.
如果我当时听凯特琳的  留在这里就好了
If I'd just listened to Caitlin and stayed behind.
你之前在现场的时候是不是速度又出问题了
Hey, you had a glitch in your speed back there, didn't you?
我用了终极速度-X提升了一下能力
I used Velocity-X to boost my powers,
但是我的身体排斥它
but my body rejected it.
凯特琳提醒过我会出现这种情况
Caitlin warned me it could happen.
我知道你不喜欢坐冷板凳
Look, I know you don't like taking a backseat,
但是在你能控制你的能力之前  巴里
but until you can manage your powers, Barry--
我知道  我应该更加小心
I know. I have to be more careful.
我们有关于烈日的任何信息吗
Do we know anything about Sunshine?
只知道她能在阳光下消失还能融化钢铁
Only that she can disappear in sunlight and melt steel.
她的名字是米莉·罗林斯
Her name is Millie Rawlins.
卡米拉在我们离开水星实验室之前照了张照片
Kamilla took a photo before we got out of Mercury Labs.
我们用了尖端科研实验室的面部识别系统
We ran it through S.T.A.R. Lab's facial recognition
在国防部数据库找到了她
and got a hit at the Department of Defense's Database.
-退役军人  特种部队  -是的
- Ex-military, special ops. - Yeah.
她通过粒子加速器爆炸
She was transferred to the covert division
得到能控制阳光的超能力之后
after the Particle Accelerator explosion
就被调到了秘密部门
left her with the meta-ability to bend sunlight.
她的呼号是烈日
Her call sign was Sunshine.
我们知道她的目标是什么吗
Do we know what she was after?
知道
Yep.
水星实验室说这是独一无二的
Mercury Labs says it's a one-of-a-kind,
高级能量转换器
advanced energy converter.
曾经属于麦克洛奇技术公司
It used to be owned by McCulloch Technologies.
他们将它称为棱镜折射器
They're calling it a Prismatic Refractor.
卡夫从他自己的公司偷的吗
Carver was stealing his own technology?
-为什么  -我们还不知道原因
- Why? - We don't know why yet,
但你俩没事我很开心
but I'm glad you two were okay.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
对不起  宝贝  我的记者思维
Sorry, babe. My reporter brain.
我很高兴你没事
I'm glad you're okay.
那东西不是应该在中城警局的证据储存室
Shouldn't that thing be at CCPD in evidence lockup?
如果卡夫想要得到
Well, if Carver's trying to get this,
我们不能冒险让他的内鬼进入
we can't risk his mole gaining access.
我给天眼会打个电话
I put in a call to A.R.G.U.S.
在他们保管它之前
Until they have it in their custody,
我不会让它离开我的视线
I'm not letting it out of my sight.
我们可以暂时把它存在
Well, we could keep it here at S.T.A.R. Labs
尖端科研实验室
for the time being.
如果烈日和光博士和致命紫光一样无情
If Sunshine is as ruthless as Dr. Light and Ultraviolet,
那她将会再次追踪这个折射器
then she's coming after that Refractor again,
如果她出现在尖端科研实验室
and if she shows up at S.T.A.R. Labs,
闪电侠做不了任何事情来阻止她
the Flash isn't gonna be able to do anything to stop her.
让天眼会保管吧
Let A.R.G.U.S. take it.
巴里有关烈日的判断是对的
Barry's right about Sunshine.
如果在转移天眼会的途中她攻击怎么办
What if she strikes during the transfer to A.R.G.U.S.?
我来弄  你去看看你的丈夫吧
Let me worry about that. Go see after your husband.
好的  当然
Yeah, yeah, of course, I was--
我正要去
I was just about to.
想逃跑吗
Wanna get away?
我只是需要一个地方思考
I just needed a place to think.
我知道失去神速力很可怕
Look, I know losing your speed is scary.
特别是斯旺还出现了
Especially with Thawne showing up.
但巴里  我爱的那个人不因为受限制
But, Barry, the man that I love would not let limits
就不去做自己最擅长的事
keep him from doing what he does best...
打败超能力者  保护人民
Taking down metas and protecting people.
闪电侠不应该有限制的  爱瑞丝
The Flash isn't supposed to have limits, Iris.
如果斯旺的超能力恢复了
Look, if Thawne gets his powers back,
我就没法阻止他
I won't be able to stop him.
就像我无法阻止烈日
Just like I can't stop Sunshine.
或许闪电不能阻止他们  但
Well, maybe the Flash can't stop them, but...
巴里·艾伦可以
Barry Allen can.
闪电侠不能和之前跑得一样快又如何
I mean, so what the Flash can't run as fast as he used to?
巴里·艾伦早在闪电侠出现前
Barry Allen was taking down villains
就开始打击坏人了
long before the Flash came along.
巴里  你就和闪电侠一样都是英雄
Barry, you are just as much of a hero as the Flash.
这是中城授予你荣誉勋章的原因
That's why the city gave you the medal of honor.
你真的打算让中城警局
I mean, are you really gonna let CCPD
自己处理烈日吗
handle Sunshine by themselves?
没有神速力我不知道怎么帮助他们
I don't see how I can help them without my speed.
巴里
Barry,
好像你困在
it's like you're stuck on this idea
闪电侠应该是无限制这个想法里了
that the Flash is supposed to be limitless,
但超能力者是有限制的
but metas are the ones that have limits.
想想吧
I mean, think about it.
如果戒王没有了圆环会怎样
Where would the Ringmaster be without his rings?
或者说蝉没有了匕首
Or Cicada without that dagger?
甚至逆闪电和烈日
Even Reverse-Flash and Sunshine,
他们也有他们的限制
they--they have their limits.
你得找出来是什么
You just have to figure out what they are.
你说得对
You're right.
烈日的确有限制
Sunshine does have limits.
我得找到乔
I have to find Joe.
卡米拉
Hey, Kamilla.
我知道折射器要运往哪
I know where the Refractor's going.
准备好行动
Get ready to move fast.
你为什么把我关在这
Why are you keeping me here?
检查了你的记忆  纳什
I went through your memories, Nash.
进行了深度探究  想出来这个好主意
I plumbed your depths. Came up with this little gem.
很糟糕  对吧
It's awful, isn't it?
黑暗
It's dark.
-消极  -纳什
- It's negative. - Nash!
-纳什  -玛雅
-Nash! - Oh, Maya.
成就突出者  对吧
Quite the overachiever. Right?
完美员工
Perfect employee.
真正的能人
A real go-getter.
当她把声波发射器
When she went to go get the Sonic Emitter
调至最高对准柯多船长  记得吧
atop the highest peak on Corto Maltese--remember that?
一鼓作气  下决心拿到发射器
And plucked that, so determined to get the Emitter.
因为毕竟
Because after all...
战利品就是一切
The prize is everything,
-不是吗  -让我走
- Isn't it? - Let me go!
想从记忆中出去吗
Want out of this memory?
请自便
Be my guest.
你不想离开这个记忆
You don't wanna leave this memory?
为什么
Why? Did--
-那个山洞里发生过什么吗  -不是我的错
- did something happen in that cave?  - It was not my fault.
-不是我的错  是她  -没错
- It was not my fault! It was her fault! - Oh, that's right.
不是我的错
It was not my fault.
她死了
She died.
不是我的错
It's not my fault!
都是你的错
It was all your fault.
是她的错  不是我的错
It was her fault. It was not my fault.
超光速粒子控制
我不明白
I don't understand.
我已经全速运行正超光子装置了
I've got the PTDs on full blast.
斯旺的负超光子应该会失去稳定性
Thawne's negative tachyon's should be destabilizing,
但是神经元数据并没有表现出任何抵抗
but the neuron data isn't showing any resistance.
唯一的变化就是他的能量在增强
If anything, his energy's intensifying.
他到底在那里对你做了什么
What the hell is he doing to you in there?
我几乎感觉不到纳什了
I barely even feel Nash anymore,
我只是  我...
I just-- all I--
我能感受到的只有恐惧和羞愧
all I feel is fear and shame all around me.
我不能  我无法
I can't-- I can't-- I don't think I can...
塞西尔  你还好吗
Cecile, are you okay?
就快好了
Almost there.
这东西拦不住我
These won't hold me.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell just happened?
斯旺连接上了他的神速力
Thawne just connected to his Speed Force.
再发生一次的话  我们就会永远失去纳什
If that happens again, we lose Nash forever.
逆闪电会重生
The Reverse-Flash lives again.
天眼会安全运输车马上就到  队长
A.R.G.U.S. Secure transports should be here any minute, Captain.
做得好  科博尔
Good job, Korber.
他们到达后立刻通知我
Let me know as soon as they land.
谢谢
Thanks.
队长
Captain.
我知道你要把那个东西转移出中城警局
I understand you're moving that thing out of CCPD custody.
我来监督转移
I'm here to oversee the transfer.
真的吗  为什么
Really? Why?
我按照你的建议做了些午餐阅读
Well, I did a little lunchtime reading as you suggested.
我同意你的说法
And I agree with you.
我认为卡夫有内应
I think Carver has someone on the inside.
我们必须自己去调查
And we need to investigate this ourselves.
谢谢  大卫
Thank you, David.
我就知道让你来领导警局没错
I knew I picked the right man to lead this precinct.
他们到了  在东装货区
They're here. East loading dock.
-出发吧  -好
- Let's roll. - All right.
多谢过来  先生们
Thank you for coming, gentlemen.
-都准备好了吗  -准备好了  局长
- You all set? - We're all set, Chief.
稍息
At ease.
小心
Look out!
大家小心
Watch yourselves.
她去哪了  她去哪了
Where'd she go? Where'd she go?
不需要再有人受伤了  各位
No one else has to burn, gents.
背靠背  背靠背
Back, back, back, back, back!
交出折射器就行
Just turn over the Refractor.
我们绝对不会给你
We're not giving you a damn thing!
-乔  -接着
- Joe! - Here.
不管你藏在哪  快出来
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
不
No!
没错  你是日光驱动者
Yep. You're helio-kinetic.
没有阳光  你就只是个普通的小偷
So without access to sunlight, you're just an ordinary thief.
能力限制太烦了  对吧
Limits suck, don't they?
那么  局里清扫完毕了
So, our house is clear,
折射器在天眼会很安全
the Refractor's safe and sound with A.R.G.U.S.
你确定没事吗  局长
You sure you're okay, Chief?
我头很痛  问问我的丈夫
Yeah, I got a hard head. Just ask my husband.
乔  如果烈日就是内鬼呢
Hey, Joe, what if Sunshine was our mole?
没人能看见她篡改那些文件
No one would have seen her doctor those files.
她确实是个完美的隐形特工
Um, she's the perfect invisible agent.
如果我们把她留在这里
Look, if we pin her down here,
她可以帮我们调查卡夫的反腐案
she can be the brick for building Carver's RICO case.
-你来吗  -不  你们去吧
- You coming? - No, you go ahead.
我还要处理别的事情
I have something else I have to take care of.
为什么没有用
Why isn't this working?
斯旺的超光速粒子增值速度
zThawne's tachyons are proliferating at a rate
超过了正超光子装置的能力
that exceeds the PTD's capabilities.
斯旺控制纳什的身体
So it's just a matter of time
只是时间问题
before Thawne takes over Nash's body.
纳什会怎么样
What happens to Nash?
其他威尔斯们又会怎样
And to the other Wellses?
他们会像活在地狱里一样
They'll be in a living hell.
永远被困在斯旺的精神里
Trapped inside Thawne's psyche forever.
他能吸收他们的知识
He'll be able to siphon their knowledge.
如果他失控了
If he gets loose,
我们不能冒险让他得到纳什的思想和那些装置
we can't risk him having Nash's mind and his gadgets.
我们得毁掉这些
We have to destroy these.
这是阿莱格拉吗
Is that Allegra?
不  是二重身
No, it's a doppelganger.
也许这就是为什么纳什经常来这里
Maybe that's why Nash hung around so much.
阿莱格拉会让他想起认识的人
Allegra reminds him of someone he knew.
让他想起  让他想起来
Reminds him... reminds him!
他所有的这些感受  所有的情感
Everything that he's been feeling, all of his emotions,
让我想起了我想到琼妮或詹娜时的感觉
they remind me of how I feel when I think about Joanie or Jenna.
差不多就是父母之心
It's--it's almost parental.
但还不只是这种感觉
But it's not just that,
还夹杂了1995年
it's mixed with the feeling that I had in '95
我妈妈去世时的那种感觉
when my mom passed away.
悲痛  天啊  西斯科
Grief. Oh, my God, Cisco.
我觉得纳什被困在了一个轮回中
I think that Nash is caught up in a loop,
充满了悔恨和悲伤
and it's made out of remorse and sadness.
负能量
Negativity.
我觉得阿莱格拉的二重身死了
I think that Allegra's doppelganger died.
还有什么能比失去孩子更痛苦
What could be more painful than the loss of a child?
塞西尔  如果你的猜测没错
Cecile, if you're right,
那么斯旺把纳什困在了她死去的记忆中
then Thawne is holding Nash in the memory of her death.
所以必须由纳什来把斯旺驱逐出去
That's why Nash has to be the one to expel Thawne.
我们要帮他
We're gonna help him.
麦德2.0
The M.A.D. 2.0.
我们用它进入过思考者的意识
We used it to get inside the Thinker's mind.
这次我们要进入纳什的意识
This time we're going inside Nash's,
我们一起把斯旺从里面赶出去
and together, we'll force Thawne out from the inside.
你确定要这么干
You sure you wanna do this?
我们不能再让你冒失去速度的风险了
We can't risk you losing anymore speed.
不会的  相信我
I won't. Trust me.
抓住  小伙子们
Hang on, boys.
路上会很颠簸
It's gonna be a bumpy ride.
这不是我的错  不是我的错
It's not my fault. It's not my fault.
不是我的错  不是我的错
Not my fault. Not my fault.
这不是我的错
It's not my fault.
这不是我的错  这不是我的错
It's not my fault, it's not my fault,
it's not my fault, it's not my fault...
斯旺  你该走了
It's time for you to go, Thawne.
你们来晚了  闪电侠
You're too late, Flash.
纳什是我的
Nash is mine.
纳什
Nash!
不  现在还不是
No, not yet he isn't.
西斯科  你来救我了
Cisco. You came for me.
对  但你才是唯一能把自己
Yeah, but you're the only one
救出这里的人  纳什
who can get yourself out of here, Nash.
你想要纳什  先过了我这关
You want Nash, you're gonna have to go through me.
你还真是喜欢自讨苦吃
Aren't you a glutton for punishment?
总是在那看着
Always there to bear witness
你拼命拯救的人死去
to the death of someone you're trying to desperately save.
这次你赢不了的
Oh, you're not gonna win this time.
我觉得我能赢  看看他
I think I am. Look at him.
听着  不管里面有什么
Hey, look, whatever's in there,
你都要去面对
I think you need to go face it.
不  不  我不能进去
No, no. I can't go in there.
他脆弱  可悲
He's weak. He's pathetic.
受制于自己的情绪
He's limited by his emotions.
就跟你一样
Just like you.
他想让你留在这里
He wants you to stay here.
你越痛苦
The more you suffer,
-他就越强大  -不  不
- the stronger he gets. - No, no.
战利品就是一切
Prize is everything.
阿莱格拉的二重身
Allegra's doppelganger.
那是她  对吗  她在里面
That's her, isn't it? She's in there.
玛雅
Maya.
她叫玛雅
Her name is Maya.
再过一会  我就能...
In a few short moments I'm gonna...
冲破西斯科的超光速粒子场  然后...
bust through Cisco's tachyon field and then...
好戏就要上演了
Then the fun's really gonna begin.
所有能量都来自于可怜的纳什
All fueled by poor Nash's grief for
对他宝贝女儿的悲痛感
his precious daughter.
你也感受过宝贝女儿死去的
You know a few things about grief
那种悲痛  对吗
for a precious daughter, don't you?
不  巴里
No, Barry.
巴里  拜托  别让他影响你
Barry, come on. Don't let him get to you.
别让他影响你
Don't let him get to you.
你没有充分利用
You didn't make the most of your time
跟女儿相处的时间
with your daughter.
我把毕生所学都教给了她
I taught her everything I know
而你却坐视不管
while you sat by and did nothing!
她选错了  就是这样
She made a bad choice, that's all.
她只是做了个选择
She just made a choice.
好了  听我说
That's all. Listen to me.
她选错了
She made a bad choice.
-听我说  -不  不行
- Listen to me! - No, I cannot!
如果你不进那个洞穴  你会死的
If you don't go into that cave, you're gonna die.
我不能进那个洞穴
I cannot go into that cave!
你所做的一切就是扼杀她的能力
All you did was stifle her abilities.
你对她来说是位糟糕的父亲
You were an awful father to her.
我天天都在思念我的女儿
I miss my daughter every day.
但我不会再任由你利用这件事控制我
But I'm done letting that give you power over me.
我看着辛西娅死去  这让我痛不欲生
I watched Cynthia die and it hurt me in places
我都不知道自己还能感觉到痛苦
I didn't even know I could feel pain.
我无法逃避
I couldn't avoid it.
逃避是无法使你痊愈的
You can't heal if you avoid it.
你觉得纳什和我都受制于自己的情绪
You think that Nash and I are limited by our emotions.
但你错了
But you're wrong.
是它们给予我们力量
They give us our strength,
我们可以用它们战胜一切
and we can use them to overcome anything.
包括你
Including you.
那是你最大的软肋  斯旺
That's your greatest flaw, Thawne.
超能力者才会有限制
Metas are the ones with limits.
人没有
Not people.
我没有
Not me.
纳什也没有
And not Nash.
你得面对那段记忆
You have to face that memory.
当你选择面对时  我会在这等着你
And when you do, I'll be here waiting for you.
我保证
I promise.
不  你别想过我这关
No, you're not getting past me.
地球13  一年前
你可以的  玛雅  小意思
You got this, Maya. Easy peasy.
纳什  最后一个记忆存储器在这
Nash! The last memory cell is here!
拿上  我拉你上来
Grab it, and I'll pull you back up.
别这么做
Don't do it.
拿到了吗
You got it?
看来这个山洞不想让这个东西离开
Guess the cave doesn't wanna let this thing go.
卡在这里了
It's stuck.
好吧  你到底了
All right, well, kay, you're at--you're at the end!
-不要这么做  -回想下你的训练
- Don't do it. - Remember your training!
战利品就是一切
The prize is everything.
阻止她
Stop her!
战利品就是一切
Prize is everything.
不要
No.
我拿到了  小意思
I got it! Easy peasy.
小意思
Easy peasy!
玛雅
Maya...
纳什
Nash!
玛雅  玛雅
Maya, Maya--
Maya! Maya!
扔了它  扔了它
Let it go. Let it go.
玛雅
Maya.
不要
No!
不
Oh, no...
是我的错
It was my fault.
她只是在按我的教导行事
She only did what I taught her to do.
这是我的错
It was my fault.
纳什已经控制住了他的伤痛
Nash has taken control of his pain.
不
No.
你不能再寄生于他了
You can't feed off of him anymore.
不
No.
-结束了  斯旺  -不
- It's over, Thawne. - No.
不  不要
No, no.
不
No!
纳什  我在这
Hey, Nash. I'm here.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
他会好的
He will be.
我需要睡一会
I need a nap.
你没事了  你没事了
You're okay. You're okay.
纳什  我在这  我在这
Nash, I'm here. I'm here.
是我的错
It was my fault.
都是我的错
It was all my fault.
卫星扫描显示
The satellite scans say there are no traces
负超光粒子搜索完成  没有检测到对象
没有在地球上任何有机物质中
of Thawne's negative tachyons
发现斯旺的负超光速粒子的迹象
to be found in any organic matter on the planet.
至于纳什
As for Nash,
塞西尔确认她没有在他身体里
Cecile confirmed that she didn't feel
感应到任何斯旺的能量
any of Thawne's energy inside.
根据三维成像
According to three-dimensional imaging,
纳什的脑电波没有斯旺的迹象
Nash's brainwaves are Thawne-free.
我想这意味着尖端科研实验室成功地完成了
I guess this means S.T.A.R Labs has successfully completed
它的第一次驱魔仪式
it's very first exorcism.
斯旺消失了  目前来说
Thawne's gone. For now.
是的
Right.
斯旺的超光速粒子可能已经消散了
Thawne's tachyons might've dissipated,
但是它们还没被摧毁
but they weren't destroyed.
也就是他还没死  只是不成型
Which means he's not dead. Just formless.
他没准现在就在外面找另一具身体
He's probably out there looking for another body right now,
像一个红了眼  气急败坏的伏地魔
like a red-eyed, pissed off, Voldemort.
他回来  我们也会准备好
He comes back, we'll be ready.
我去看看纳什
I'm gonna go check on Nash.
你还  你还好吗
Are you, uh-- are you good?
我也有个人要去看看
I have someone I should check on too.
那是什么样的
What was it like?
像在雾里
Like being in fog.
你知道那像什么吗  就像在水底
You know what it was like? It was like being underwater.
我能看见  我能听见
I could see, I could hear,
但是它很  很朦胧  我什么都做不了
but it was--it was hazy, I couldn't do anything--
基本上  糟透了
well, basically, it sucked.
你摆脱它了  摆脱了斯旺
You're free of it. Free of Thawne.
至于其他的威尔斯们
As for the other Wellses,
他们的脑电波
their brainwaves are unfortunately
还是不幸的和你的纠缠在一起
still entangled with yours.
所以他们现在也算是你的一部分了
So they're as much a part of you now as yourself.
好吧
Right.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
-你是说我会一直听到...  -没错
- You mean I'm gonna keep hearing-- - Yeah.
-我还会一直看到他们  -没错
- I'm gonna keep seeing them. - Yeah.
无限威尔斯危机
Crisis of infinite Wells.
不过更糟的我都挺过来了
Well, I've had worse.
这事没什么可炫耀的
Hey, look, credit where credit is due.
我知道如果没有你的帮助
I know that without your help,
我不可能把那个疯子赶出我的身体
we don't get the psychopath out of my body,
因此我非常感谢你
so for that, I'm grateful.
谢谢
Thank you.
始源地球见  孩子
See you around Earth-Prime, kid.
你是不是忘记什么东西了
Aren't you forgetting something?
应  应该没有吧
I--I don't think so.
我干这行的过程中发现了很多东西  但是...
I made a lot of discoveries in my career, but...
我最美好的发现...
the best discovery...
她对我  她...
You know, she treat-- she was...
她对于我来说...
Just like a daughter...
就像女儿一样  所以...
to me, so...
-阿莱格拉呢  -阿莱格拉怎么了
- And Allegra? - What about Allegra?
她当然不是玛雅
Sure, she's not Maya,
但你确实帮助过她掌握她的超能力
but you did help her with her powers.
但你也知道  我们一开始相处得并不愉快
But, you know, we got off to a rocky start.
所以也没必要闹僵了再分开
There's no point in making it a rocky ending.
-纳什  -又怎么了
- Nash. - What?
选择一个威尔斯  哪个都行
Pick a Wells. Any Wells.
-我必须这么做吗  -不
- Do I have to? - No.
没关系的  我和所有人一开始都相处得不好
It doesn't matter; I got off to a rocky start with all of them.
-你想说什么  -我想说的是
- What's your point? - My point is,
我明白要把你对一个人的感情
I get how difficult it is to separate your feelings
和他们的二重身上分离出来有多困难
about a person from their doppelganger.
我告诉过你我是怎么遇到哈里的吗
Did I ever tell you about the time I met Harry?
没有  是地球二的威尔斯吗
You didn't. That's the Earth-2 Wells?
就是那个
The very one.
好吧  继续说
All right, go ahead.
我第一次遇见他的时候
When I first saw him,
我当时的眼里只有艾尔伯德·斯旺
all I could see was Eobard Thawne.
但当我看到他时
But when I saw him,
当我真正看清哈里的为人之后...
when I really saw Harry for who he was...
我成为了他的朋友
I became his friend.
他也成了我的朋友
He became mine.
是的  你和阿莱格拉一开始并不交好
Yeah, you got off to a bad start with Allegra,
但去建立美好的事物永远不嫌晚
but it's not too late to build something good.
你是个好人
You're a good egg.
你不会因为我开始多愁善感了吧
You're not getting sappy on me, are you?
没有
No.
-很好  -很好
- Good. - Good.
他说得对
He's right.
拉蒙  他有第二次机会和阿莱格拉在一起
Ramon, he had a second chance with Allegra.
我们一直想要告诉你的就是这个
It's what we've been trying to tell you.
你总觉得自己最聪明了
You think you're so smart.
说完就走
And he's gone.
这可要费些时间才能习惯
Well, that's gonna take some getting used to.
凯特琳  我必须向你道歉
Caitlin, I-- I need to apologize.
我没有听取你的建议
I didn't follow your advice,
你会受伤都是因为我
and you got hurt because of me.
-对不起  -没关系  巴里
- I'm sorry. - It's okay, Barry.
我快好了  已经感觉好多了
I'm on the mend. Feeling better already.
那我们没事了吧
So, we're okay?
当然
Always.
状况报告  纳什身体健康
Status report: Nash is physically fine,
不过内心崩溃了  而西斯科已经彻底累坏了
but emotionally destroyed, and Cisco is completely bushed.
你们俩和好了吗
You guys make up yet?
谢天谢地
Thank God.
伙计们  我们确定制造一个人工的神速力
Guys, are we sure creating an artificial Speed Force
是个好主意吗  我是说
is the way to go? I mean,
凡是接触过斯旺的神速力的人都受伤了
anyone who came in contact with Thawne's Speed Force got hurt.
我们不会那样
Ours will be different.
没错  不过我们还是不知道该怎么着手准备
Yeah, but we still don't even know where to start.
其实我知道
Actually, I do.
每次斯旺想要伤害我都会利用诺拉的记忆
Every time Thawne tried to hurt me using Nora's memory,
但正是因为他这么做才让我记起我有多么爱她
really what he did was reminded me how much I loved her.
让我意识到她就是答案
Made me realize that she's the answer.
诺拉的日记
Nora's journal?
斯旺教会了诺拉如何去制造神速力
Thawne taught Nora how to build a Speed Force.
现在她可以教我们了
Now she can teach us.
没人看到你吧
And no one saw you?
中城警局都在忙着对付烈日
CCPD was busy fighting Sunshine.
大家都忙进忙出  没人注意到我们
In and out and no one noticed.
看来我的丈夫虽然不再找我了  但...
So my husband stopped looking for me, but...
很显然  他却会出去寻找我的玩具
apparently still goes out looking for my toys.
你们做得非常好
You did very well.
只要我们严格按照计划执行...
And as long as we stick to the plan...
-我们就一定能成功  -我们就一定能成功
- Success is assured. - Success is assured.
而我距离自由也只有一步之遥了
And I'm one step closer to liberation.